All right. We're uh
we're excited about today. Um you know,
not just with the players that we added,
the three guys that we added, but um
also how we were able to add to our um
our resource base uh in 27. Um and then
how we're positioned for for tomorrow
afternoon. Um you know, with several
other day three picks. So, uh obviously
a lot of action, a lot of movement um
you know, throughout the evening
tonight, but we're pleased with where we
ended up. And so, with that, I'll open
up with questions.
didn't come tonight you make this many
trades but when you get a sense that it
could be just that kind of night
>> it's usually just based on the action
that you get or how the board falls. Um
I'll be honest Dan like we're pretty
like we try to stay pretty nimble and
flexible just because you never know you
know when the next opportunity is going
to come up. I think that's actually one
of the benefits of having volume and
quality with your picks because there
are more opportunities to maneuver up
and down the board. Were you surprised
with some of the guys that fell in your
lap like
to begin with first round progressions?
>> I was probably most surprised with Eman.
Um, you know, we figured that Denzel
could go anywhere from late one to to
early two just to be truthful. Um, but
Eman, he wasn't someone that we
anticipated being, you know, being there
as late as he was. So, um, when he got
within striking distance, you know, we
felt the move was appropriate. You know,
to be truthful, he was in play for us at
39.
what you did with your wide receiver
room. Can you sort of talk about what
you have globally from your pass
catching right now and how this might
impact like a Jerry Judy or anybody like
that?
>> Zero impact on Jerry. He's our bellcow.
Um we feel like we have a nice uh I
think with receiver rooms you can have,
you know, maybe a ball dominant player
or you can essentially build a
basketball team, you know, with
different skill sets. Um you know, we
prefer the the second approach. Now,
don't get me wrong, I'll take Calvin
Johnson if he's if he's out there, but
um we feel like we have a nice, you
know, well-rounded room with speed,
rack, um contested catch ability,
separation. Um so, we're we're really
pleased with um you know, the youth and
talent in that group.
>> On that trade, uh for Emanuel, do you
get a sense that another team is going
to take or when do you know when to pull
the trigger on?
So there they're there they're there
probably two separate situations, Jeff.
Um one is when you and one is when you
do have maybe an inkling that you know
you're going into a a stretch where um
you know a player or a group of players
you know will be target for several
teams and you're trying to get ahead of
it. Another may just be um and I would
put like the Emanuel trade and then what
we did for JK in 2021 in this bucket
where you have a player that you just
didn't expect to be in a certain range
of the draft and there's a certain level
of like, okay, you don't necessarily
have a a team identified that's going to
take that player off the board, but you
look at your resources and say, hey,
this is a price that I'm I'm willing to
pay for this skill set for this guy. Um
relative to what you think you're
getting.
I'll go here and then I'll go Ashley.
>> You talked last week before the draft
just about that positionless defense.
Um, where does where does a player like
Emanuel Emil Warren sort of fit into to
that that idea as you think about what
you got in him as a player?
>> Yeah. Well, I Emanuel is incredibly
versatile and and you know, we're um
realistic that you're not going to put
everything on his plate his rookie year.
Um, but I think you really started
seeing this with the safety positions,
certainly with what Baltimore did with
Kyle Hamilton a couple years ago. Um,
you look across the league and you see
uh just the increase of three safety
packages. You look at what um you know
Emanury, Nick Mory did for for Seattle
this past year and it just gives you a
lot of flexibility where you have
safeties that can play deep, they can
play in the box, they can live in the
linebacker world, they can live in the
the the nickel world and um they just
give a lot of flexibility for a creative
coordinator.
>> Remember last year after the guys
drafted Carson, we talked about the
importance of taking off linebacker that
high. You hadn't made a major investment
there since like four years prior. Was
there any similar Emanuel like you
hadn't taken a safety that high since
Grant like six years ago.
>> No, it it really wasn't because you know
Grant and Ronnie we obviously like those
guys a lot. Um you know Grant we I mean
we took him my first draft. We extended
him. Um you know Rocket he's
outperformed how we acquired him signing
him in as an undrafted free agent. um
Emanuel, it was I mean it we just viewed
it as a fantastic opportunity and
someone who could you know not only just
from a pure talent standpoint improve
the room but could also complement our
existing core there.
>> Um uh you spoke back in January about
dedicating a lot of resources to
remaking this offense
>> with one day still left in the draft.
Do you where do you how do you how do
you feel about the process you've done
in terms of that remodeling?
>> Uh I think we're excited about the
players that we've added. U we're
certainly excited to see them on the
grass because we haven't seen them as a
collective unit. Um, you know, but we
still have we still have work to do on
both sides of the ball and and and
tomorrow will be a big day for that, but
um, you know, so will, you know, really
made to the cut down period because
there are still some um important roles
that we'd like to add competition to.
>> You don't want to put too much on
Emanuel's plate too soon. Do you see him
initially as kind of a ballhawk free
safety?
>> I think that remains to be seen, uh,
Tony. Um, and and honestly like that
determination will be by, you know,
Monk, Rudy, Ephraim. Um,
yeah, I I it's it's probably hard for me
to answer that until he's in our
building until we get him up in up and
running. Um, but, you know, we'll we'll
crawl, walk, run.
>> I know you have to stay flexible during
the draft, but did you anticipate a
scenario where you might take two
receivers either back to back or
whatever early in this draft and does it
feel like like a departure because you
really haven't done that in your
previous drafts taking receiver high
>> Scott we did um we did have scenarios
where because of the strength of the
receiver class and the depth of it that
we thought we could take um you know two
receivers relatively high definitely
doesn't feel like a departure it's maybe
a little bit you know what I mentioned
to Fred earlier where I think if you
look at the past couple years you know
we had we had Jarvis and Odell Um, you
know, we traded for Amari, who was a Pro
Bowl receiver for us, and then, you
know, had him on a big money extension.
We then traded Jerry for Jerry, who was
a Pro Bowl receiver for us. Um, and then
like I was actually even thinking, um,
and this this one didn't maybe work out
quite as cleanly, but even the years
where we were short first round picks,
you know, one of those trades was for
Elijah Moore and then, you know, trading
down from two for Elijah Moore and then,
uh, taking set in three. So, there's no
philosophical thing there. It's
obviously easier to to maybe dictate the
room a little bit more when you have
your full slate of resources.
>> Tom, about how the quarterbacks looked
on the last two days of mini camp
because we didn't get to see any of
that. Um, so just wondering how
comfortable are you with quarterback
room right now and what are you still
thinking that it's wholly realistic to
possibly add somebody to the room on the
third day of the draft?
>> Yeah, we'll always add talent at the
most important position. That's that's
that's, you know, I guess full stop.
Doesn't matter who's in the room. if
there's a quarterback that we'll like
that's available to us at the right
cost, we'll add that player. Um, you
know, that being said, the three guys
have done a really nice job so far this
spring. You know, we're lucky that we
got three days on the grass. Um, you
know, they all are are learning the
offense quickly. Um, you know, working
through their mistakes, throwing the
ball, throwing the ball well. Um, but,
you know, that wouldn't that wouldn't
um, you know, prevent us from adding a
player that we like tomorrow.
>> Ging all this stuff out. Was there a
scenario where you had your first four
picks all was Cleveland Browns? I mean,
just seems like four players that a lot
of people had first round grades on
I know a couple years ago with JK
there, but it feels like you got two of
them here.
>> Yeah, I I think um you know, as we work
through scenarios, as we work through
simulations, uh we did have simulations
where the receivers kind of lined up the
way that they did um just because of the
strength of this class. You know, I'll
be honest. I I did not anticipate a
world where um Emanuel went as late as
he did.
>> Step out of the third round then back
in. Did you overlook Austin?
>> No. So, I actually called those yo-yo
trades. So, like sometimes you get um a
situation actually probably the first
time I started calling it was that when
we um moved back in was actually Sashi I
think we moved back in 17.
um picked up a future one and I think we
moved back up for for David at the end
of one. Um oftentimes those trades
become like if you look at the aggregate
set of moves, they become pretty
efficient because you pick up either a
high level or future asset um but you're
able to still get a targeted player
without giving all those realized gains
back. Very rare situations will we do
that, but we felt like this was one
where it made the most sense.
>> Special affinity and
The fifth round is the new seventh. Mary
Kay. Yeah. So,
>> what's the thinking going into tomorrow
with fourth round?
>> You know, honestly, in day three of the
draft because teams, boards, they they
they just spread out there. There's
there's very little overlap. Truth be
told, you could largely go into the
third day of the draft with maybe call
like eight to 10 names and you're
probably going to get you're probably
going to get most of them. So, it it
it'll literally be, hey, how can we be
as opportunistic as possible because
you're just not going to be able to
predict, you know, predict the order of
uh, you know, the players that go off. I
was joking with Todd upstairs. I was
like, man, I I got apologize. I misread
the market because,
um, you know, we thought we were going
to be able to maybe add one of the
class's strongest, you know, blocking
tight ends, you know, with one of those
fifth round picks. And, you know, pretty
much all of them went off the board by
the end of the third round. So, I was
like, I screwed that one up. I messed
that up. So, we'll just take the best
opportunity that we can with the players
that are available. I don't know who
mentioned it earlier. If there if there
comes a situation where there's a u a
veteran trade that makes sense, we would
explore that as we always do. But, um
our big thing is how do we best maximize
the assets?
>> Um do you see Todd said you see first as
a tackle?
>> Um so, is that just about I mean
obviously traded or signed traded for
Titus and then draft Spencer. So, is it
that position is so important that you
want to get as much depth outside.
>> Yeah. I mean, I also think like, you
know, we talked about turning over that
position group um with both youth and
talent. And um Titus is great. Um he can
play tackle, he can play guard, um but
also being realistic that um you know,
he is a little bit more advanced in his
career, you know, relative to some of
the other players. But you can never you
can never have enough of the of the
tackles. you can never have enough of
the, you know, the line of scrimmage
players just because they're so hard to
find and they're so hard to acquire once
you get past this point that um we want
to roll deep in those position groups
when we can.
>> Looking at the players that have gone
first 100, only three running backs, do
you attribute it to class? Do you
attribute it to I mean just in in your,
you know, kind of your scouting of that
position? Like can you what would you
>> I think it's two things. I think it's
class and I also think it's um just the
fact that if you go back to last year's
class how deep it was. I think a lot of
teams took took their young running
backs. I mean look we took two um and so
I think that plays into it as well.
>> Considering why Emanuel fell like he
did.
>> I don't just some sometimes that happens
just happens.
>> How long
you know, trying to it's way past my
bedtime. So, I I that that is one of the
hardest parts of this weekend. You just
get or I speak for myself, I get so
drained. one because I'm an early
morning person and then two just from
everything that you're doing um you know
in terms of of trying to manage and
direct you know the evening the day the
quick turnaround um and then honestly
just all the like kind of the ancillary
obligations that that come as part of
it. Um they are long days. So
>> think about the move to eight minutes in
the first round.
>> Love it. like like yes I this may be
unpopular but I would make it seven
minutes if we can. So yes
patience you thought you guys showed by
not moving up staying there then Zel
makes it to you guys and then obviously
you made a couple other moves when you
went up. So, what would you say is a
determining factor to when they say
we're going to stay and wait and hope
versus let's go get back?
>> I mean, you're you're really trying to
just play the odds and and and when I
say that, it's it's not just like this
black bods, okay, this guy has whatever
percentage chance of getting there. It's
pulling
um you know, the information that you
can source. It's looking at your board
and and identifying the group of players
that you're comfortable with sitting and
picking or you know, if you have to
move. Um, and then at that point it's
making an educated guess. Like look, we
did consider, okay, if we're at 39, is
there a move that would make sense to go
up and get Denzel or go up and get, you
know, Emanuel? And after going through
all the information, having discussion,
um, you know, kind of trying to read the
board as the picks came off, we felt
like the right decision, the right bet
was to remain to remain patient. And you
don't get all those right. Um, you know,
so you know, you just make the best
decisions you can in the moment.
>> How much fun has it been just having
videos?
>> It's it's it's great because like Todd
is super funny and um unfortunately all
of it can't make it on camera with how
funny he is, but he is he keeps the room
energetic. He keeps it light. He's super
passionate. Um he's he's a lot of fun to
work with. So
>> ask him that the next time he comes down
here. How about that? All right, you
guys have a good night.